# N.P Senthil Kumar

Senior Technical Lead

## Contact

**Phone** 999-497-3303

**E-mail** npsenthil@gmail.com

## **Skills**

C#.Net

Very Good

Asp.Net

Very Good

Sql Server

Very Good

**JavaScript** 

Very Good

Crystal Reports

Good

SharePoint

Good

Tech support to team

Very Good

- SSIS
- Service Now
- JIRA
- SharePoint

Having 18+ Years of experience in analysis, design and development on the web based applications using Microsoft .Net Technologies. Currently working as **Senior Technical Lead** in **HCL Technologies**. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. Strong in guiding other teammates and solving complex issues with the team. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices .

## **Work History**

#### 2011-01 -Current

### Senior Technical Lead

**HCL Technologies Ltd.** 

•

- ITAO (IT Application) owner for 20 applications
- Responsible to own the 20 applications.
  Enhancement, Bug fixing, migration activity for those 20 applications.
- Provide support to the team technical and nontechnical.
- Communicate with customers, collect requirements.
- Complaint checks for the applications.

#### 2007-06 -2010-10

## Senior Software Engineer.

Angler Technologies Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu.

- Product development team.
- Responsible for develop and enhancement of web applications which are developed in ASP.net, ADO.net, JavaScript, MS SQL.
- Developed new system that would be used to track the employee attendance and shift management.
- Provided client support for the applications.
- Lead team to understand flow of codes in programming units for further development and improvisation of applications.

#### 2002-08 -2007-05

# **Software Programmer**

Selvam Systems Pvt Ltd, Sivakasi, Tamil Nadu.

- Responsible to develop web based applications in Classic ASP.
- Develop web applications using ASP.net, MS SQL.
  Deployment and maintained the application.

# **Education**

**B.Sc. Computer Science** Nadar Saraswathi College of Arts and Science, Theni, Tamil Nadu

P.G.D.C.A - Indira Gandhi Open University

• Name : N.P Senthil Kumar

• Father's Name : N. Paramasivam

• Date of Birth : 28-May-1980

• Gender : Male

• Marital Status : Married

• Languages Known : English, Tamil

• Nationality : Indian

#### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the above furnished information is true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge.

N.P SENTHIL KUMAR